Let's go ahead and continue to style our at entry screens here.
我们继续对添加条目屏幕设置样式
You'll notice looking at these final versions that there are some things different.
查看这两个最终版之后 你会发现一些不同之处
You'll notice the buttons are a little bit different based on what platform we're on.
不同平台上的按钮有所不同
You'll also notice that
还会注意到
these increment decorative buttons are a little bit different too.
这些递增和递减按钮也不同
So it's something we'll have to keep in mind as we style this.
因此 在设置样式时我们需要注意这些
First, let's go ahead and import a few things from react-native.
首先 从 react-native 中导入一些内容
We're going to need platform so we can see what platform we're currently on
我们需要导入 Platform 以便知道当前位于哪个平台上
and then we're also going to use the style sheet API.
还需要使用 StyleSheet API
Here, what we can do is,
我们转到下面
let's go down here and create some styles,
在这里创建一些样式
which is going to be the result of calling StyleSheet.create and what I first want
它将是调用 StyleSheet.create 的结果
to do is let's first go ahead and style the submit button up here.
我们首先对这里的提交按钮设置样式
What we'll do is,
我们将
let's create a iOS submit button,
创建一个 iOS 提交按钮
and then we will create an Android submit button because as I talked about,
然后创建一个 Android 提交按钮
they're a little bit different and then we will create a submit button text,
因为我提到它们有所不同
which is going to be the same on both platforms.
然后创建提交按钮文本 两个平台上是一样的
Let's do the text first. We're going to have a color of
先设置文本样式
whites and we need to go ahead and import this
颜色为 white 需要导入 white
up here so we'll import white from utils/colors and then now,
在这里输入 import  from ‘../utils/colors’
our text is also going to have,
然后将文本的
say font size 22 and then we will make sure the text align is center.
fontSize 设为 22 并将 textAlign 设为 center
Then now, the iOS button,
对于 iOS 按钮
what we're going to have here is,
我们将 backgroundColor
let's say the background color is going to be purple,
设为 purple
which we also need to import real quick and then on top of the background color,
还需要快速导入 purple
what we're also going to have,
然后在 backgroundColor 上方
this will give it a padding of 10,
将 padding 设为 10
border radius is going to be 7, height,
borderRadius 设为 7
we'll say is 45 and then margin left and margin right are both going to be 40
height 设为 45 marginLeft 和 marginRight 均设为 40
and then the Android's submit button is going to be similar so
Android 提交按钮类似
it's also going to have a background of purple and a padding of 10,
backgroundColor 设为 purple padding 设为 10
say padding left though is going to be 30,
paddingLeft 为 30
padding rights is also going to be 30, height 45.
paddingRight 也设为 30 height 设为 45
Border radius, it's going to be a little bit smaller than iOS. We'll just say two.
borderRadius 比 iOS 平台要小些 设为 2
We're going to align it at the end and
alignSelf 设为 flex-end
then everything inside of it is going to be justified and aligned center.
里面的所有内容居中对齐
Now, what we can do is let's go ahead and add these styles to our button.
现在将这些样式添加到我们的按钮上
We have our button up here and then we will say,
按钮在这里
style if we are on iOS.
输入 style 如果位于 iOS 上
The styles we want to apply to this button are going to be styles.iOS submit button.
我们将向此按钮应用 styles.iosSubmitBtn 样式
If we're not on iOS,
如果不位于 iOS 上
which means we're on Android,
则位于 Android 上
we're going to apply the Android submit button styles.
我们将应用 androidSubmitBtn 样式
Then texts, no matter what platform we're on,
对于文本 无论我们位于哪个平台上
we're going to say style is equal to styles.submitButton text.
style 都为 styles.submitBtnText
Now, if we look at this,
现在看看应用界面
if everything is working,
如果一切正常
you'll notice that we have a button down here and eventually,
你会在下方看到一个按钮
when we fix the styling on this one we'll be able to see the Android button.
最终当我们设好 Android 按钮的样式后 将在这里看到 Android 按钮
Now, let's go ahead and continue to add styles here.
现在继续在这里添加样式
What we can do is let's come to our styles.
转到 styles() 中
We will have a container,
在这里设置一个容器
which is going to be around the main container
它将是主容器
and almost always whenever you have a container component,
几乎每当我们添加容器组件时
as we do right here,
就像在这里
you'll want to give it a flex of one so its children will take up all of the space
都需要将 flex 设为 1 以便其子容器占据整个所有空间
say padding 20 and then we'll give it a background color of white.
将 padding 设为 20 然后将 backgroundColor 设为 white
Let's go ahead and apply this here, Styles.container.
在这里应用该样式 输入 styles.container
Now, let's go ahead and apply some styles to this.
现在在这里应用一些样式
What we want to have happen here,
你会发现
you'll notice this is the thing that we're mapping over,
我们将映射这些内容
instead of these being aligned in a column,
默认情况下 这些垂直对齐
as they are by default, we actually want to align them in a row.
但是我们希望能水平对齐
We can say is let's say style equals styles.row and then here in our style sheet,
输入 style = styles.row 然后在 StyleSheet 中
let's add a row, which is going to say,
添加一个 row
flex direction of row so it's setting the main access to row, flex: 1.
输入 flexDirection: ‘row’ 将主轴设为横向 将 flex 设为 1
It'll take a couple of space and then we want to align items along the cross axis,
它将占据所有空间 希望沿着交叉轴对齐内容
which is going to be vertical center.
即垂直居中
If we look at our app, there we go,
看看应用界面
just hit refresh on Android.
刚才在 Android 上点击了刷新
It's looking a lot better.
看起来好多了
We have now these rows.
现在有这几行内容
Now, the last thing I want to styles if you remember,
最后要设置样式的是这个视图
we have this view right here.
还记得吧？
let's go ahead and style that,
我们为其设置样式
and that's just coming from the section right here.
对应的是这个部分
First, let's go ahead and we all make a little container for this, we'll call it center.
首先为其设置一个容器 称为 center
What we want to do is basically just align or have everything positioned in the center.
我们希望一切都居中
Say flex: 1, justify content is going to be centered,
因此输入 flex: 1 justifyContent 设为 center
align items are going to be centered,
alignItems 设为 center
margin left and margin right are both going to be set to
marginLeft 和 marginRight 都设为 30
30 and then we will apply this styles to this view right here.
然后将此样式应用到这里的视图上
That way, it's going to center everything.
这样一切将居中
Now, all we need to do is let's go ahead and give this just an inline style.
然后在这里设置内嵌样式
We'll add some padding to it so we'll say padding is going to be,
添加一些内边距
let's just say 10 pixels and then now,
将 padding 设为 say 10 像素
if we submit one of these again,
现在再次提交这些内容的话
you'll notice that we get this icon right here.
你会发现我们将图标放在了这里
What I want to do is I want to have
我希望在不同的平台上
a different icon depending on what platform you're on because there are more
显示不同的图标
Android and iOS specific smiley faces I guess so we can say is, inside of iOSicons.
因为肯定有具体的 Android 和 iOS 笑脸图标
Instead of just having iOS-happy-outline,
在 Ionicons 中
what we want to say this will say,
对于 iOS-happy-outline
if we are on iOS,
如果我们在 iOS 平台上
then have the name be iOS-happy-outline and if we are not,
则名称还是 iOS-happy-outline
meaning we are on Android,
如果不在 iOS 上 则在 Android 上
then we will say md-happy,
名称设为 md-happy
which stands for material design happy and so that way,
表示 Material Design 笑脸图标
if we refresh both of these then we submit both of these.
然后刷新这两个应用并提交这些内容
You'll notice that the icon is a little
你会发现在不同的平台上
bit different depending on which platform you're on.
该图标有所不同